Guide to the Gilman Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Diaries, Writings, Financial and Personal Papers of Gilman Family Members, 1818-(1850-1900) 1932; Series III; 5' (12 boxes)
  - Gilman family, General
    - Visitor books, Gilman family (Flushing, New York, 1883-1895 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Gilman Family, Individual Members
    - Arthur C. Gilman
      - Graduation oration, 1872 (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Reminiscence about, by unidentified, author, undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Benjamin Clark Gilman
      - Compass Rose, undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - Photos of clocks made by Gilman (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Caroline T. Gilman
      - Correspondence re: Jonathan Trumbull Professorhip of American Government, 1922-1923 (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - Diary re: trip to Mexico, 1879 (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Diaries and calendar books, 1868-1878 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Diaries, calendars, and address books, 1879-1883 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - Diaries and calendar books, 1884-1888 (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Diaries and calendar books, 1889-1899, 1918 (Box 24, Folder 36-37)
      - Travel journals and passenger lists, 1888-1889 (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - Family estate, (the Coit Elms), journals and plans, 1904-1915 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Caroline T. Gilman
      - Account books, 1864-1865, 1878-1890, 1920-1921 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - Stock statements, 1911-1914 (Box 25, Folder 40a)
      - Family records and genealogy, 1874 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Edward W. Gilman
      - Diaries and calendar books, 1845-1856, 1863-1871, 1884-1896 (Box 25, Folder 42-44)
      - Diaries re: church, 1849-1871 (Box 26, Folder 45)
      - Account books, 1843-1882, 1839-1859 (Box 26, Folder 46-48)
      - Account books, 1860-1870, 1868-1885 (Box 27, Folder 49-52)
      - Account books, 1885-1892, 1891-1900 (Box 28, Folder 53-54)
      - Stock statements, 1878, 1894, 1898, 1900 (Box 28, Folder 54a)
      - Address, "Faith Wadsworth Hubbard", 1887 (Box 28, Folder 55)
      - Printed articles: "From Easter to Ascension Day"; "Before Easter"; "The Relations Between Benevolent Societies and the Congregational Church"; "Living, Though Once Dead"; "Life and Immortality"; "A Doubting Disciple", 1890-1894, undated (Box 28, Folder 56)
      - Miscellaneous printed articles, 1849-1900, undated (Box 28, Folder 57)
      - Articles written for or about Bible Society (Box 28, Folder 58)
      - Scrapbook containing printed articles and addresses by Gilman, 1856-1879 (Box 29, Folder 59-60)
      - Guide to West Point, 1844 (Box 29, Folder 61)
      - Sermons, 1849-1855, 1857-1869, 1886, 1900, undated (Box 29, Folder 62-66)
      - Sermons, list of titles and Scripture, 1858-1868 (Box 29, Folder 67)
      - Notes on Scriptures, undated (Box 29, Folder 68)
      - Notebook re: religion, [1851?] (Box 29, Folder 69)
      - Church membership lists and historical sketch of Congregational Church, Bangor, Me., 1857-1862 (Box 30, Folder 70)
      - Student course notes and essays, 1842, undated 1845-1847, undated (Box 30, Folder 71-72)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1840, 1870-1883, 1891, undated (Box 30, Folder 73)
      - Photos, 1866, undated (Box 30, Folder 74)
      - Book lists, 1839-1840, undated (Box 30, Folder 75)
    - Elizabeth Coit Gilman
      - Essay, "A Question", 1847 (Box 30, Folder 76)
    - Hattie Gilman
      - Tribute on the death of Miss Read, 1847 (Box 30, Folder 77)
    - Julia S. Gilman
      - Diary of a European trip, 1888 (Box 30, Folder 78)
      - Memoirs (manuscript), "A Mid-Victorian Little Girl", 1926 (Box 30, Folder 79)
      - Memoirs and reminiscences, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 80)
      - Household accounts, 1868-1869, 1872-1875, 1888-1892 (Box 30, Folder 81)
    - Louise Gilman
      - Diaries and travel journal, 1882-1884, 1889 (Box 30, Folder 82)
      - Account books, 1882, 1888-1892, undated 188-1890, undated (Box 31, Folder 83-84)
      - Photos, 1857, 1867, 1871, 1883 (Box 31, Folder 85)
    - Maria Perit Gilman
      - "Passages in the Life of a Saint", 1906 (Box 31, Folder 86)
      - Memorial tribute, 1907 (Box 31, Folder 87)
      - Photos, 1857, 1901, undated (Box 31, Folder 88)
    - Serena Gilman
      - Inventory of estate, 1881 (Box 31, Folder 89)
    - William Charles Gilman
      - Diaries, 1834, 1850 (Box 31, Folder 90)
      - Biographical fragments, undated (Box 31, Folder 91)
      - Family newspaper, "The Cricket on the Hearth", 1850 (Box 31, Folder 92)
      - Photos (Box 31, Folder 93)
      - Scrapbook, 1852 (Box 31, Folder 94)
      - Boy's Meeting and Sabbath School (Box 31, Folder 95)
- Subjects Files, 1848-1929; Series IV; 1' (2 boxes)
  The SUBJECTS FILES contains correspondence, photos, newsclippings, and an assortment of printed and manuscript materials arranged alphabetically by subject category.
  - Abbot Collegiate Association
    - Notes and printed matter, 1848, 1856, 1858, 1904-1905 (Box 32, Folder 95)
  - Connecticut Indian Association
    - Correspondence re: Indians, 1876-1899 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Photos of Indians, 1883, 1891, 1898-1899 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Printed matter, 1898-1927 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Bible Society
    - Printed matter, including articles by Edward W. Gilman, 1888-1899, 1896, 1900 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Boy's Meeting and Sabbath School
    - Constitution, minutes and membership lists, 1851-1852 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Congregational Church
    - Charters, rules, and statements of belief, 1853-1872 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Printed matter, 1858-(1862-1900)1918 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Missionary Society
    - General laws and act of incorporation; speech of Sancho the Proverbialist, 1848 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Norwich, Connecticut
    - Printed matter re: history of Norwich, 1906, 1908, 1914, 1921, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Vacation school, reports, accounts, and printed matter, 1852, 1884, 1901-1904 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Silliman Family
    - Biographical fragment on Gold S. Silliman, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Genealogical materials, 1888, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Last will and testament,(copies) of Benjamin D. Silliman, 1900 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Photos. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Printed matter (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Trumbull Family
    - Genealogical materials (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Photos (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - News clippings re: Jonathan Trumbull (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence and printed matter re: Jonathan Trumbull Professorship of American Government, 1922-1923 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Oversize
    - Genealogy, photographs (Box 34)
    - Genealogy (Box 35)